Onondaga County Community College Presidents' Collection
Onondaga Community College
- Office of Dr. Francis Almstead (February 1962 - December 1967), 1962 - 1967; Archival material related to the Presidency of Dr. Francis Almstead. Almstead was the first President of Onondaga Community College. He was President from February 1962 to December 1965. Almstead obtained a B.S. and M.S. 
  - Correspondence with Other Colleges, 1962 - 1965; Correspondence to other Community Colleges. (Box-folder PRE1 - 2, PRE2A)
    - Letter from Philip C. Martin, President of Westchester Community College, regarding Professional Personnel Committee, July 26, 1965; Typed letter from Philip C. Martin, President of Westchester Community College, regarding suggestions for meeting of the Professional Personnel Committee. Suggests writing a short review of the Professional Service Law.
    - Letter from Philip C. Martin, President of Westchester Community College, regarding Finance Law, September 16, 1965; Typed letter from Philip C. Martin, President of Westchester Community College, asking Almstead what his thoughts were about a new Finance Law.
    - Letter from Walter E. Rauch, Chairman of Liberal Arts and Business Curriculum at Weschester Community College, regarding Questionnaire, February 19, 1965; Typed letter from Walter E. Rauch, Chairman of Liberal Arts and Business Curriculum at Weschester Community College, asking if one of his assistants could fill out a questionnaire for a panel titled "Homogeneous Grouping of Students for the Improvement of Teaching Procedures."
    - Letter to Philip C. Martin, President of Westchester Community College, regarding Finance Law, October 29, 1965; Typed letter to Philip C. Martin, President of Westchester Community College, responding that OCC was not having an issue with a new Finance Law.
    - Letter to Paul B. Orvis, Executive Dean, State University of New York, 1962 - 1965
    - Letter to John Garfola, Onondaga Community College, June 30, 1965
    - Letter to and from Samuel B. Gould, President, State University of New York, 1964 - 1965
    - Letter from Donald G. Eichmeyer, Assistant Secretary, State University of New York, November 28, 1962
  - General Correspondence, 1962 - 1967; Correspondence with various people, state agencies, and organizations. (Box-folder PRE1 - 3)
    - Letter from Frank E. Hobson Jr., State Education Department, regarding Visit to Onondaga Community College, January 25, 1965; Typed letter (with hand-written notations) from Frank E. Hobson Jr., State Education Department, with his recommendations for improvement to OCC after his visit to campus.
    - Thank-you Letter to Paul M. Glaude, September 14, 1962; Typed letter thanking Paul M. Glaude, thanking him for visiting with the foreign languages faculty.
    - Thank-you Letter to Congressman R. Walter Riehlman, October 2, 1962; Typed letter to U.S. Congressman, R. Walter Riehlman, thanking him for his expression of kind thoughts toward the college.
    - Letter from Congressman R. Walter Riehlman in Response to Almstead's Thank-You Letter, October 4, 1964; Typed letter from Congressman R. Walter Riehlman noting that he had received Almstead's thank-you note and that he would like to visit OCC after his campaign is over.
    - Memo to George Domohowski Regarding Locks, July 8, 1963; Typed memo to George Dmohowski asking if it would be a good idea to combine locks so that one key could open multiple doors.
    - Letter from J. Cameron Thomson, Chairman of Business Education Committee, November 24, 1964; Typed letter from J. Cameron Thomson, Chairman of Business Education Committee, informing Almstead that the Trustees of the Committee for Economic Development have issued a policy statement regarding the education of tomorrow's business leaders.
    - Letter from S. Avery Raube, National Industrial Conference Board, regarding Fellowships, August 17, 1967; Typed letter from S. Avery Raube, Vice President of Division of Personnel Administration, National Industrial Conference Board, regarding articles the National Industrial Conference published on company sponsored fellowships for students. Articles are included with letter.
  - Correspondence with Onondaga Community College Faculty and Staff, 1962 - 1967; Letters and memos to and from OCC faculty. (Box-folder PRE1 - 4)
    - Memo on Closed Circuit Television in Education, 1962 - 1967; Undated typed memo, by Almstead, on how to set up closed circuit TV for educational use (only first page included-pages missing).
    - Memo on Faculty Responsibilities and Hours of Work, 1962 - 1967; Typed memo, by Almstead, on faculty duties and hours of work.
    - Memo on Staff Luncheon, May 31, 1962; Typed memo to all staff about having a staff luncheon at Drumlins Country Club.
    - Memo on Telephone Usage, September 13, 1962; Typed memo to faculty and staff on telephone use and checking message slips.
    - Thank you Letter from George J. Dmohowski, October 6, 1962; Typed letter from George J. Dmohowski, thanking Almstead, thanking him for being pleasant to work with. Dmohowski also mentions his work helping the School open.
    - Memo to Faculty on Reporting Arrival and Departure, October 15, 1962; Typed memo asking faculty to report to Mrs. Eells, the receptionist, when they are coming into the building and out of the building so she can handle incoming calls properly.
    - Memo to Mrs. McCarty regarding United Nations Week, October 15, 1962; Typed memo to Mrs. McCarty, asking if she had anything planned for students for United Nations Week.
    - Memo from Faculty Academic Committee regarding Organizational Structure, October 22, 1962; Typed memo from the Academic Committee (Howard Faulkner, Harold Russell, C. Richard Rhoades, George Mulligan, George Dmohowski, Donald Nellenbach) outlining their recommendations for how positions at the College should be organized and structured.
    - Memo Regarding Biology Lab Student Assistants, October 22, 1962; Typed memo to Mr. Oney and Mr. Malek informing them Almstead is allocating $175 for Biology lab student assistants.
    - Memo Regarding Chemistry Lab Student Assistants, October 22, 1962; Typed memo to Mr. Singh informing him that Almstead is allocating $350 for student Chemistry lab assistants.
    - Memo Regarding Dental Hygiene Student Assistants, October 22, 1962; Typed memo to Dr. Russell informing him that Almstead is allocating $175 for student assistants in the Dental Hygiene Lab.
    - Memo Regarding Physics Student Assistants, October 22, 1962; Typed memo to Mr. Mulligan and Mr. Nellenbach, informing them that Almstead is allocating $200 for student assistants in the Physics lab.
    - Memo to Dr. Delbalzo Regarding Allocation of Funds for Special Supplies, October 23, 1962; Typed memo to Dr. Delbazo informing him that Almstead is allocating $500 for special supplies and expense items for the year.
    - Memo to Mr. Faulkner Regarding Allocation of Funds for Special Supples, October 23, 1962; Typed memo to Mr. Faulkner informing him that Almstead was allocating $1000 for special supplies and expense items for the year.
    - Memo to Mrs. Downes and Mr. Singh Regarding Allocation of Funds for Special Supplies, October 23, 1962; Typed memo to to Mrs. Downes and Mr. Singh, informing them that Almstead was allocating $1000 for special supplies and expense items for the year.
    - Memo to Mr. Rhoades Regarding Allocation of Funds for Special Supplies, October 23, 1962; Typed memo, to Mr. Rhoades, informing him that Almstead was allocating $500 for special supplies and expense items for the year.
    - Memo to Mr. Nellenbach Regarding Allocation of Funds for Special Supplies, October 23, 1962; Typed memo to Mr. Nellenbach, informing him that Almstead is allocating $3000 for special supplies and expense items for the year.
    - Memo to Dr. Russell Regarding Allocation of Funds for Special Supplies, October 23, 1962; Typed memo to Dr. Russell, informing him that Almstead was allocating $1000 for special supplies and expense items for the year.
    - Memo to Mr. Mulligan Regarding Allocation of Funds for Special Supplies, October 23, 1962; Typed memo to Mr. Mulligan, informing him that Almstead was allocating $3000 for special supplies and expense items for the year.
    - Memo to Mr. Faltyn Regarding Allocation of Funds for Special Supplies, October 23, 1962; Typed memo to Mr. Faltyn, informing him that Almstead was allocating $500 from money paid by students for supplies and expense items.
    - Memo to Mr. Faltyn Regarding Allocation of Funds for Geology, October 23, 1962; Typed memo to Mr. Faltyn informing him that Almstead was allocating $500 to be used for special supplies and expense items. Handwriting on memo says "Geology."
    - Memo to Faculty and Staff on Person in Charge While Almstead Absent, October 24, 1962; Typed memo informing faculty and staff that George Dmohowski would be in charge of the College while Almstead was attending a Regents convocation in Albany.
    - Memo to Mr. Faltyn Regarding Geology and Physical Science Student Assistants, October 31, 1962; Type memo to Mr. Faltyn informing him that Almstead was allocating $200 for student assistants in the Geology and Physical Science labs.
    - Memo to Glenn Williams Regarding College Adviser for Student Newspaper, November 9, 1962; Typed memo to Glenn Williams informing him that Almstead was appointing him as adviser to the student newspaper.
    - Memo to Faculty Regarding Guidance Counselors Visiting Campus, November 19, 1962; Typed memo to faculty giving information on a visit by guidance counselors to campus.
    - Memo to Faculty Regarding Student Attitudes, December 4, 1962; Typed memo to faculty asking for them to give a list to Mr. MacDonald of students with "adverse" attitudes in the classroom.
    - Memo to Faculty Regarding Student Attendance, December 4, 1962; Typed memo to faculty regarding student attendance policy at OCC, specifically what is considered "tardiness" and what is considered an "absence."
    - Memo to Faculty Regarding Student Attendance List, December 6, 1962; Typed memo to faculty asking for a list of students who have 3 or more "cuts" to be sent to Mr. MacDonald. Paper torn-possibly incomplete.
    - Memo to Faculty Regarding Top of Faculty Meetings, December 10, 1962 - December 17, 1962; Typed memo to faculty informing them of the topic of two faculty meetings in December, 1962.
    - Memo to Faculty Regarding Christmas Party and Faculty Meeting, December 10, 1962; Typed memo informing faculty that Almstead would like to hold a faculty meeting before a Christmas party, sponsored by Bersani.
    - Memo to Miss Davenport and Dr. Delbalzo Regarding Language Laboratory, January 2, 1963; Typed memo to Miss Davenport and Dr. Delbalzo informing them the language lab was closed until repairs could be made. Damage to lab caused by students.
    - Summary of November 1965 Faculty Meeting, November 18, 1965
    - Note Regarding Faculty Roles, 1962 - 1965; Typed note listing names of faculty and their roles within the College.
    - Memo to Faculty Regarding Mid-Year Exams, January 8, 1963; Typed memo to faculty regarding grading policy for mid-year exams.
    - Memo to John MacDonald Regarding Dennis E. Sands, February 5, 1963; Typed memo to John MacDonald, asking him if he could help guide, Dennis E. Sands, an instructor in electrical technology, in learning his duties in his new job.
    - Memo to Faculty Regarding Minutes of SUNY Board of Trustees Meeting, March 19, 1963; Typed memo to faculty informing them that the SUNY Board of Trustees had resolved that tuition and fees for SUNY community colleges was waived for academic employees.
    - Memo to Faculty Regarding Shoplifter, January 15, 1963; Memo to faculty informing them that Almstead was "reasonably sure" that a woman who saw in a hallway was a shoplifter.
    - Memo to Faculty Regarding Requests for Leave of Absence, April 22, 1964; Typed memo to faculty asking them to fill out a form if they wanted to request a leave of absence. Includes Application for Leave of Absence Form.
    - Memo to Faculty Regarding Student Evaluations, April 29, 1963; Typed memo to faculty asking them to try evaluating students in "non-academic areas" such as self-discipline, oral expression, resourcefulness, etc.
    - Memo to English Department Regarding New Faculty Member, April 30, 1963; Typed memo to the English Department informing them that R. Wayne Archer has joined the English Department.
    - Memo from Howard H. Burtis Regarding Transfer Credit, July 23, 1963; Typed memo to Almstead, from Howard H. Burtis, informing him that the Board of Trustees was interested to what extent other colleges were accepting credits from OCC, and that Burtis will get information on how many students are requesting transcripts sent to other colleges.
    - Memo from C. Richard Rhoades Regarding Almstead Inauguration Ceremony, July 26, 1963; Typed memo from C. Richard Rhoades, informing faculty and staff that the inauguration ceremony for Almstead that was scheduled for November was being post-poned by the Board of Trustees.
    - Memo to Faculty Members Regarding State Education Department Visit, September 9, 1963; Typed memo to Mr. Burtis, Mr. Larsen, Mr. MacDonald, Mr. Zahm, and Mrs. MacDonald regarding a campus visit from Edward F. Carr, Associate in Higher Education of the State Education Department.
    - Memo to Faculty Members Regarding Academic Affairs Council, September 13, 1963; Typed memo to Professors Bertan, Faltyn, Gammon, Leon, Mr. Gray, and Mr. Weathers informing them that Professor Faltyn will represent the physical science unit on the Academic Affairs Council, replacing Dr. Larsen.
    - Memo to Faculty and Staff Regarding Re-Organization of Staff, September 25, 1963; Typed memo to faculty and staff informing them that John Garfola, a Student Personnel Services staff member, would be looking at the functions of the office staff and administrators and propose a plan on how to most efficiently organize staff.
    - Memo to Mr. Krall Regarding Fire Drill, September 26, 1963; Typed memo to Mr. Krall asking if he could be the contact person for the Fire Marshall for a fire drill.
    - Memo to D. Heil, Bookstore Manager, Regarding Purchase of Furniture, September 27, 1963; Typed memo to D. Heil, the bookstore manager, regarding faculty members purchasing furniture from Penfield Manufacturing Company.
    - Announcement Regarding Student Exam, 1962; Typed one-paged announcement regarding a test to be administered on Wednesday, Nov. 28.
    - Memo to Faculty and Staff Regarding Library Hours, October 2, 1963; Typed memo to faculty and staff on the library hours for the school year.
    - Memo to Faculty and Staff Regarding Activities with the Switchboard Operator, October 7, 1963; Typed memo to faculty and staff asking them to register all faculty, staff, and student activities with the switchboard operator. Also has information regarding reserving rooms and the college car for activities.
    - Memo to Faculty Regarding Plan for Solving Problems, October 22, 1963; Typed memo to faculty regarding plan to communicate and solve problems. Includes a diagram of chain of command for who to communicate to when a problem occurs.
    - Memo from Richard A. Cobb Regarding Student Closed Circuit TV Presentation, 1963; Typed memo to, Almstead and Dean Burtis, from Richard A. Cobb, Coordinator of Television Activities and Audio-Visual Aids, inviting them to watch a presentation from the Television Production Class.
    - Memo to Faculty Regarding Solutions to Problems, October 28, 1963; Typed memo to faculty on what Offices to contact when dealing with academic problems. Includes explanation of what each Office can help with.
    - Memo to Staff Regarding Surveys and Questionnaires, December 10, 1963; Typed memo to Staff informing them to send completed surveys and questionnaires to the Office of the Director of Information.
    - Memo to Mr. DeBlasis Regarding Proposed Television Production, January 6, 1964; Typed memo to Mr. DeBlasis asking if his drama group would be interested in writing and producing a play about life at OCC. Almstead expresses desire to film the production for future use.
    - Memo to Faculty and Staff Regarding Student Personnel Services Assignments, January 31, 1964; Typed memo to faculty and staff informing them of changes in assignments and responsibilities within the Student Personnel Services Office, specifically referring to Dean MacDonald and Mr. Garfola.
    - Memo to Faculty Members Regarding Meeting on Admission Policy, February 4, 1964; Typed memo to Deans Burtis, Larsen, MacDonald, and Flansburg, Garfola, Henderson, Russell informing them of a meeting to be held for developing a plan for admission policy.
    - Letter from Philip G. Klein Regarding Payroll Deductions, February 6, 1964; Typed letter from Philip G. Klein, Faculty Co-Secretary, requesting Almstead to have payroll deductions be shown in written form on faculty paychecks.
    - Memo to Ransom G. MacKenzie Regarding Vocational and Technical Training and Facilities, March 2, 1964; Typed memo to Ransom G. MacKenzie, summarizing a meeting about where to have vocational and technical training facilities and if community college program in vocational and technical training could succeed in the area.
    - Memo to Richard Cobb Regarding Public Address System, April 10, 1964; Typed memo to Mr. Cobb asking Cobb to submit a report on changes and procedures involved for re-locating the public address system. Includes Cobb's request to move the public address system from the audio visual room to the telephone switchboard room.
    - Memo to Robert Malek Regarding Medical Laboratory Technicians, April 28, 1964; Typed memo to Robert Malek on some of Malek's students becoming medical laboratory technicians at Upstate Medical.
    - Memo to Howard Faulkner Regarding Meeting with New York State Industrial Arts Teachers, May 11, 1964; Typed memo to Howard Faulkner approving of a meeting with the New York State Industrial Arts teachers.
    - Memo to Faculty Members Regarding Pharmaceutical Curriculum, May 15, 1964; Typed memo to Deans Burtis and Larsen, Mrs. Swerdlow, and Dr. Russell, asking them to attend a meeting with Dean Leverman of Columbia University about the possibility of creating a pharmaceutical curriculum.
    - Memo to Howard Faulkner Regarding Commencement Speaker, May 21, 1964; Typed memo to Howard Faulkner, informing him that Senator Carl Curtis accepted the invitation to speak at Commencement.
    - Announcement Regarding President of SUNY, May 21, 1964; Typed announcement from Almstead that Samuel B. Gould would be President of the State University of New York starting September 1, 1964.
    - Memo to Faculty and Staff on Policy for Identifying Candidates for Graduation, May 27, 1964; Typed memo to faculty and staff asking for their reactions to the Policy and Procedures for Identifying Candidates for Graduation.
    - Memo to Professor Archer Regarding Summer Employment, June 23, 1964; Typed memo to Professor Archer informing him that, due to there being less in the "honey bucket," there would be 7 weeks, not 10 weeks, of summer employment.
    - William G. Dwyer Speech, "Behind the Door", June 17, 1964; Typed copy of William G. Dwyer's speech, "Behind the Door" from a Community College Workshop at SUNY Farmingdale.
    - Memo to Faculty and Staff Regarding Change of Assignments and Appointments, June 26, 1964; Typed memo to faculty and staff regarding John MacDonald taking over the General Studies Program and John M. Parker joining the College as Dean of Student Personnel Services. Includes brief C.V. of Parker.
    - Memo to J.H. Mullaley Regarding Two New Hires, July 7, 1964; Typed memo to J.H. Mullaley, informing him of two new hires, Mrs. Arrain and Mr. Bedell.
    - Letter to Dr. Daniel Burdick Regarding Meeting to Discuss Nursing and Medical Laboratory Technology Programs, July 13, 1964; Typed letter to Dr. Daniel Burdick asking to arrange a meeting to discuss how Burdick could assist with formulating Nursing and Medical Laboratory Technology programs.
    - Letter ffom Professor John T. Henderson Regarding Gramercy Guild Group Graphics Award, July 21, 1964; Letter Professor John T. Henderson, Electrical-Mechanical Technology gave to Almstead about an Award given to a company out of Colorado to students showing achievement in a graphics course. Includes letter received from Gramercy Guild Group-sponsor of the award.
    - Memo to Faculty Members Regarding Appointment of Dean of the College, August 13, 1964; Typed memo to Mr. Murray, Mr. Flansburg, and Dean Parker informing them that Howard H. Burtis was appointed Dean of the College, effective Sept. 3, 1964.
    - Memo from Dean Larsen Regarding Federal Funds, August 18, 1964; Typed memo from Dean Larsen asking Almstead asking for clarification on how the college can obtain federal funds.
    - Memos Regarding NYSTA Meeting at OCC, September 30, 1964; Typed memos between Howard Faulkner and Almstead about a meeting at OCC with the Industrial Arts Division of the NYSTA.
    - Memo to Dean of Women Regarding Student Residency at the Mizpah Hotel, October 13, 1964; Typed memo to the Dean of Women stating that Miss Rice and Miss Regan can stay at the Mizpah Hotel while being students.
    - Memo to R. Wayne Archer Regarding Nassau Community College Staff Publication, November 16, 1964; Memo to R. Wayne Archer stating he was attaching a staff publication from Nassau Community College (not included with memo). Asks Archer's thoughts on OCC Faculty having their own publication.
    - Memo to Professor Rhoades Regarding Recording of Student Choir, November 17, 1964; Typed memo to Professor Rhoades asking for a recording of the choir for two talks.
    - Memo to Dean John Parker Regarding List of 1964 Graduates, November 17, 1964; Memo to Dean John Parker asking for a list of the 1964 graduates.
    - Memo to Faculty Regarding Presenting Faculty Constitution to Board of Trustees, November 19, 1964; Typed memo to faculty stating that he had sent the faculty constitution to members of the Board of Trustees. States his support of the faculty.
    - Memo to Faculty and Staff Regarding Holiday Party, December 21, 1964; Typed memo to faculty and staff informing them that he would miss the holiday party due to a meeting with SUNY President Gould.
    - Memo to Nancy K. McCarty Regarding Mimeographed Materials, January 15, 1965; Typed memo to Nancy K. McCarty asking her to review materials to be mimeographed to see if the materials are suitable for classroom use.
    - Memo from Nancy K. McCarty Regarding Mimeographed Materials, January 15, 1965; Typed memo from Nancy K. McCarty informing Almstead that the stencils had already been mimeographed.
    - Memo from John Henderson Regarding Participation in Federal Programs, January 25, 1965; Typed memo from John Henderson stating that in order to participate in federal programs such as the Economic Opportunity Act, the College would need to hire an additional secretary to handle the record keeping. Advises a transfer of funds from the capital category to personnel services in order to hire a secretary.
    - Memo to Department Chairmen Regarding Meeting with Board of Trustees, March 11, 1965; Typed memo to the Department Chairmen, asking if they will meet with the Board of Trustees.
    - Memo to George Dmohowski Regarding Board of Trustees Meeting Invitation, March 12, 1965; Typed memo to George Dmohowski stating he mistakenly included him in an invitation to meet with the Board of Trustees and that it was unnecessary for Dmohowski to attend. Attached is a hand-written note from Glenn Williams to Almstead that states he will be at the Board of Trustees meeting at Marine Midland Bank.